{"tossups": [{"question": "According to folklore, despite achieving success with this system, Zhong Kui banged his head to death on a palace gate after being refused the \u201czhuang yuan\u201d title because he was too ugly. The title of\u201cjinshi\u201d was granted to the best participants in this system, who were required to write the \u201ceight-legged essay.\u201d Participants in this system sometimes snuck undergarments containing notes on the Six Arts and Five Classics with them to cubicle rooms. For the point, name this standardized system used to select bureaucrats in imperial China since the Han Dynasty.", "answer": "Chinese<b> civil service exam</b>inations (accept<b> imperial exam</b>s or<b> keju</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "One of these institutions of \u201cNorth America\u201d was created by the Congress of Confederation at the urging of Robert Morris. George Washington appointed Samuel Howell, David Rittenhouse, and Thomas Willing to oversee one of these institutions staunchly opposed by Thomas Jefferson. In an attempt to win the Election of 1832, Henry Clay rushed the recharter of one of these institutions leading to it being swiftly vetoed. Nicholas Biddle led, for the point, what type of institution, the \u201cSecond National\u201d of which was destroyed by Andrew Jackson?", "answer": "national<b> bank</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this battle, Task Force 34, under the command of Willis Lee, was moved away from a defensive position at the San Bernadino Strait to pursue a decoy force. William Halsey\u2019s actions in this battle were derisively called \u201cBull\u2019s Run\u201d as he abandoned the endangered 7th Fleet. Admiral Kurita withdrew from this battle which would be the last major action of the Japanese navy until Operation Ten-Go. For the point, name this largest naval battle of World War II which deprived Japan of much needed oil by allowing the invasion of the Philippines.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Leyte Gulf</b> (accept Battle of the<b> Sibuyan Sea</b>; accept Battle of<b> Surigao Strait</b>; accept Battle of<b> Cape Engano</b>; accept Battle off<b> Samar</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In<em> The Eye Opener</em>, one thinker from this school argued for the use of the \u201cgentle arguments\u201d and\u201cbreak and subdue\u201d methods after his followers in Kamakura were persecuted. An earlier thinker from this school of thought outlined the fourfold negation method of logic, which he term \u201cCatuskoi.\u201d That founder of this school\u2019s \u201cmiddle way,\u201d or Madhyamaka, also posited this school\u2019s idea of \u201cabsolute nothingness.\u201dFor the point, name this school of thought followed by Nichiren and Nagarjuna, which was founded after Siddartha Guatama found enlightenment under the Bodhi Tree.", "answer": "<b> Buddhism</b> (accept<b> Nichiren</b> Buddhism or<b> Mahayana</b> Buddhism; accept<b> Madhyamaka </b>before mentioned)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This event was chronicled in the journal of James Morrison, who described how a foraging party in Nomuka became enraged after their leader refused to let them use weapons. The arrival of the Pandora brought an end to this event, whose participants had originally been sent on a breadfruit-gathering mission. This event\u2019s perpetrators fled to Tahiti and Pitcairn Island, the latter of which is now primarily inhabited by their descendents. For the point, identify this event in which Fletcher Christian led an uprising against William Bligh on a Royal Navy ship.", "answer": "mutiny on the HMS<b> Bounty</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Gotthold Lessing speculated that bourgeois society was the \u201coffspring\u201d of this organization, and J\u00a8urgen Habermas compared this organization to French and British salons and caf\u00b4es. Emmanuel Schikaneder defended this organization in a libretto for an opera where Sarastro helps Tamino defeat the Queen of the Night. Members in this organization are classified into degrees and meet in lodges. Mozart was a member of, for the point, what frequent target of conspiracy theories, a secret society which originated from medieval builders\u2019 guilds.", "answer": "The<b> Freemasons</b> (accept<b> Masons</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "One of these works begins with a strong dominant seventh chord followed by a descending run and is in the same key as another one of these works which is entirely arpeggios in both hands, nicknamed\u201cOcean.\u201d Oscillating sixteenth notes make up most of the<em> cantabile</em> right hand\u2019s lower voice in one of these works, whose melody its composer claimed was the most beautiful he ever wrote. The November Uprising inspired one of, for the point, what set of works including ones nicknamed \u201cTristesse\u201d and\u201cRevolutionary,\u201d technically difficult piano pieces by a Polish composer?", "answer": "Fr\u00b4ed\u00b4eric<b> Chopin</b>\u2019s<b>\u00b4Etudes</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This writer presented the dubious story that Pharaoh Sesostris led a campaign in Europe, but he also accurately described the flooding of the Nile. This writer\u2019s most famous work begins by describing the rapes of Io, Europa, and Medea. Croesus learns that a mighty empire will fall from the Oracle at Delphi in that work by this writer, which also details the rise of the Persian Empire and the battles of Mycale, Plataea, and Marathon. For the point, name this ancient Greek writer from Halicarnassus, author of<em> The</em> <em>Histories</em>, known as \u201cThe Father of History.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Herodotus</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "At one meeting, this activist, intimidated at having to speak after Wendell Phillips, instead sang an original song titled \u201cI am Pleading for My People.\u201d This activist accompanied George Thompson to the Ohio Women\u2019s Rights Convention in Akron where Marius Robinson recorded her as saying \u201cI have plowed and reaped and husked and chopped.\u201d For the point, name this former slave and women\u2019s rights activist who declared \u201cI can carry as much as any man\u201d in her speech \u201cAin\u2019t I a Woman.\u201d", "answer": "Sojourner<b> Truth</b> (accept Isabella Belle<b> Baumfree</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this state, the catastrophic failure of the St. Francis Dam ended the career of William Mulholland. This state is home to a desalination plant named for longtime civil servant Claude Lewis. In 1913, Fred Eaton began a campaign of lies and subterfuge to secure rights to the Owens River in this state, which he then ordered diverted which destroyed the economy of the Owens Valley. The Tuolumne [too-AWL-um-nee] River originates in a national park in this state and currently feeds the Hetch Hetchy aqueduct. For the point, name this state where water shortages have affected cities such as Los Angeles.", "answer": "<b> California</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This politician\u2019s influence diminished after he tried to commute John Porteous\u2019 sentence for firing on protestors. The Licensing Act was passed to prevent enemies of this man from expressing dissent in theatre. This man\u2019s tenure was dubbed the \u201cRobinocracy\u201d and included the introduction of a \u201csinking fund\u201d to combat the South Sea Bubble. He oversaw the War of Jenkin\u2019s Ear in his 21 years of service, the longest ever for a prime minister. For the point, identify this prime minister to George I and II, the first to hold the role.", "answer": "Robert<b> Walpole</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The loss of Guanajuato prompted Bishop Manuel Abad Queipo to excommunicate this man. After his betrayal at the Wells of Bajan, this man stated \u201cI shall be remembered forever, you all will soon be forgotten\u201d before his execution by firing squad. This partner of Ignacio Allende won a victory at Monte de las Cruces but was later captured after the Battle of Calderon Bridge. During an 1810 Mass, this man denounced the new Spanish monarchy in the<em> Grito de Dolores</em>. For the point, name this pioneering leader of the Mexican independence movement.", "answer": "Miguel<b> Hidalgo</b> y Costilla", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Hugh Wheeler\u2019s troops and family were massacred in this event after an offer of safe passage was revoked by Nana Sahib. Tensions during this event were fueled by the Doctrine of Lapse, which annexed the land of adopted princes. This event began when Mangal Pandey was hung after attempting to shoot Henry Baugh. Cawnpore and Lucknow were placed under siege during this event, which began after army cartridges were rumored to contain beef and pork fat. For the point, name this 1857 event in which Indian soldiers mutinied against their British officers.", "answer": "<b> Sepoy</b> Mutiny (accept<b> Indian Rebellion of 1857</b> before mention)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Sir Leonard Woolley discovered a golden helmet belonging to this civilisation\u2019s King Meskalamdug. This civilisation\u2019s \u201cKing List\u201d describes one city as the first in the world; that city, Eridu, was founded in the Ubaid period of this civilization. Eannatum of Lagash conquered an empire across most of this civilization, which built a \u201cGreat Ziggurat\u201d in one of its cities and invented cuneiform. The cities of Uruk and Ur formed part of, for the point, what earliest known civilization, which was based in Southern Mesopotamia?", "answer": "<b> Sumer</b>ian Civilisation", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This scientist\u2019s PhD thesis investigated the density and porosity of coal, which was used to improve gas masks. This scientist discovered that all tobacco mosaic virus particles were the same length. This scientist discovered the \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d forms of one molecule while working as an x-ray crystallographer at King\u2019s College. A diffraction pattern taken by this scientist was shared by Maurice Wilkins without her knowledge. For the point, what scientist\u2019s \u201cPhoto 51\u201d demonstrated that DNA had a double helix but was not credited by Watson and Crick?", "answer": "Rosalind<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {"question": "After the first naval battle of WWII, the Admiral Graf Spee sheltered in the port of this country\u2019s capital. This country was briefly known as the Cisplatine Province until an insurrection led by the Thirty-Three Orientals. The Italian Legion was raised in this country by the \u201cHero of Two Worlds,\u201d who fought in this country\u2019s civil war with the Colorados against the Blancos. For the point, name this country whose capital lies on the Rio de La Plata at Montevideo.", "answer": "<b> Uruguay</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This battle began when Alfred Henderson\u2019s scouts fled at the sight of enemy troops at the Oscarberg. Eleven Victoria\u2019s Crosses were given to the victors of this battle, who were led by John Chard and Gonville Bromhead in their defense of a hospital. The victorious side in this battle constructed a perimeter around Otto Witt\u2019s mission station using mealie bags and biscuit boxes. Fought on the same day as the Battle of Isandlwana, for the point, identify this 1879 battle in which 150 British troops held off 4,000 Zulu soldiers.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Rorke\u2019s Drift</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A house on this city\u2019s \u201cBillop\u2019s Point\u201d was where the only peace negotiation of the Revolutionary War occurred. The steamboat<em> General Slocum</em> sank in this city in 1904, leading to the deaths of over 1,000 people. This city\u2019s Duane Street contains an African Burial Ground national monument. This city\u2019s Colored Orphan Asylum was burned down in this city\u2019s 1863 draft riots. The 1811 Commissioner\u2019s Plan created this city\u2019s grid-like structure above Houston [HOW-ston] Street. For the point, name this consolidated city comprised of boroughs that include Brooklyn and Manhattan.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event,<em> p\u00b4etroleuses</em> were falsely accused of being paid for arson. Louise Michel dared a military tribunal to sentence her to death for her involvement in this event, but was instead deported to New Caledonia. 147 people involved in this event were shot at the Mur des F\u00b4ed\u00b4eres after this event was suppressed by General Patrice MacMahon during the Bloody Week. For the point, what 1871 revolutionary government refused the authority of Adolphe Thiers\u2019 Third Republic and was located in the French capital?", "answer": "<b> Paris Commune</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "With Robert Wagner and Allen Ellender, this politician championed the urban renewal-focused Housing Act of 1949. The final profile in John F. Kennedy\u2019s<em> Profiles in Courage</em> concerned this man\u2019s opposition to the Nuremberg trials. Clauses requiring an 80 days notice period without a \u201ccooling-off period\u201d and a strict ban on jurisdictional strikes were included in an anti-union law co-written by this man and Fred Hartley. This \u201cMr. Republican\u201d lost the 1952 Republican nomination to Dwight D. Eisenhower. For the point, name this Ohio Senator, the son of the 27th President.", "answer": "Robert<b> Taft</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}